

Md. Omor Faruk

House # 24 Road #10, Flat # 2A, Shekertak, Mohammadpur, Dhaka-1207.

omorfaruk2010@gmail.com

Mobile: 01926504116

Career Objective:

Desire to be a part of vibrant and leading organization and create footprints as a Software Developer to assist the organizations in all aspects by utilizing all my skills, knowledge, abilities and experience with a balance of hands-on, management and leadership responsibilities.

Educational Qualifications:

Master of Science (M.sc) in Computer Science

Institution name: Jahangirnagar University

Department: Computer Science Result: CGPA 3.23 out of 4 Scale

Passing year: 2018

Bachelor of Science (B.sc) in Computer Science and Software Engineering

Institution name: American International University-Bangladesh

Department: Computer Science Result: CGPA 3.39 out of 4 Scale

Passing year: 2016

Higher Secondary School Certificate [H.S.C]

Institution name: Dhaka State College

Board: Dhaka.

Year of Completion: 2011

Result: GPA 4.10 out of 5 Scale

Secondary School Certificate [S.S.C]

Institution name: Ramgonj High School

Board: Comilla

Year of Completion: 2009.

Result: GPA 4.88 out of 5 Scale.

Job Experience:

- 1. IT Executive (Software) at ACME Laboratories Ltd.
- -from August 2019 to 31 May 2020.

Job Description:

- -Development and maintenance ACME Pharmaceuticals Sales Applications (Oracle)
- -Development and maintenance of MIS sales report (PHP).
- -Development of Executive Canvas(Laravel).
- -Development and maintenance System for International Business Division (IBD).

2. Jr. IT Executive (Software) at Premier Cement Mills Ltd.

-from November 2018 to July 2019.

Job Description:

- -Development and maintenance Premier Cement Sales Application (Android)
- -Development and maintenance of ERP system (Dream Apps ERP).
- Server Management.
- Report generating from databases with crystal report and jasper report.

3. Android application Developer at Rapid PR.

-from August 2017 to July 2018.

Job Description:

- -Development of Android Application for Bangladesh tourist police.
- -Development of Rapid Seba android Application.
- -Development of Gari kena becha.

4. Web application Developer at **World Tech Org** (intern).

-from June 2017 to August 2017.

Job Description:

- -Development of management system for **Rahat Anwar Hospital** (Barsishal)
- -Testing developed system.
- Training Hospital management.

Software Development Skills:

- 1. Good knowledge in C, C++, Java, PHP (Laravel).
- 2. Knowledgeable in HTML5, CSS3.
- 3. Knowledgeable in UML.
- 4. Good knowledge in Android and XML.
- 5. Knowledgeable in Database (SQLite, MYSQL, ORACLE, SQL Server), Normalization, Entity Relationship Diagram.
- 6. Knowledge in making web application using PHP, MySOL.
- 7. Knowledgeable in Networking related field, Cisco Packet Tracer 6.2. Router Setup (TPLINK).

Fields of Interests: ACM Programming Contest (UVA ID "faruk01"), Banking, Web Application, Quality Assurance and Testing, Data warehouse & Data mining Network and Network Security, Reading, Travelling, Be Accustomed to New Application.

Project Experience:

- 1. Rapid PR Hotline (Google play store).
- 2. To-Do Application Using Laravel.
- 3. Pre-Registration Management System using JAVA Swing
- 4. Restaurant Management System Using C#
- 5. Online Shopping Management System using PHP and MYSQL (group project).
- 6. Point Of sale using PHP and MYSQL.
- 7. CRUD application using Codeigniter and bootstrap.
- 8. Restaurant Management System (Laravel & Bootstrap)
- 9. Research on Increasing Data Security and Reliability with Conceptual Foundation for Image Related Data Loss Prevention.

Personal Information:

-Father's Name: Kalim Ullah. -Mother's Name: Farhana Akter. -Date of Birth: 01 June 1993 -Nationality: Bangladeshi

-Religion: Islam

-Present Address: House # 24 Road #10, Flat # 2A, Shekertak, Mohammadpur, Dhaka-1207.

- **Permanent Address:** House # 24 Road #10, Flat # 2A, Shekertak, Mohammadpur, Dhaka-1207.

Language Efficiency:

Bengali, English.

Training:

- -Top-Up IT Training (JAVA) arranged by LICT BCC Government of Bangladesh.
- -Android Application Training at Shikhbe-Sobai.

Extra-curricular activities:

Volunteer at TEDxAIUB, Jaago Foundation.

References:

Mashiour Rahman

Assistant Professor and Director, Faculty of Science & IT (Computer Science)

American International University-Bangladesh

E-mail: mashiour@aiub.edu Cell: + 88 01711521065

Hasan Muhommod Sabbir

General Banking In charge Natore Branch

Southeast Bank Ltd.

Email: muhammad.sabbir@southeastbank.com.bd

Cell: +88 01641726787